# Mario Antollini

Java SDK Developer at Stormpath

antollinim@gmail.com

## Summary

https://github.com/mrioan

During the last eight years, Mario has mainly focused on research, development, consultancy and evangelization of Java-based backend technologies: SOA, ESBs, Messaging, SCA and Cloud technologies in particular. He has also developed end to end web applications for different SMBs, working directly with clients to successfully improve their core businesses. Mario has written three international publications and one technical book. Mario actively contributes to open source projects.

#### Technical Skills:

- Distributed Systems: J2EE (EJB3, EJB2.1, MDB, JMS, JNDI, JAAS), Web Services (Axis2, JAX-RPC), RMI, XML, SOA, ESB
- Web Servers: Tomcat
- Back-end: JBoss, Glassfish, Google App Engine, IBM WebSphere
- Front-end: Play Framework, (Smart)GWT, Vaadin, JSP, HTML, Struts, Javascript
- CASE tools: IBM Rational XDE Developer, Enterprise Architect
- Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, Python, Objective-C, OpenGL
- IDEs: IntelliJ IDEA, Eclipse, Netbeans, IBM WebSphere Studio, KDevelop
- OSs: Mac OS, Linux, Windows
- DBMSs: MySQL, H2, Cassandra, MS SQL Server 2000, Oracle, DB2, MaxDB
- DB related: Hibernate, JPA, JDBC, ODBC, SQL
- Mobile: iPhone development
- Issue tracking: Bugzilla, Jira, Rally, Redmine
- Additionally: Maven, Git, SVN, ant, VM experience (VMware, XEN, VirtualBox), Splunk, QTP, linux scripting, windows scripting, AutoIT

Citizenship: Argentinean and Italian.

Willing to telecommute.

# Experience

Java SDK Developer at Stormpath

#### June 2014 - Present (2 years 9 months)

- Development: Spring Boot, Thymeleaf, Spring Security integration, JWT, OAuth2, Servlet, Open Source, Social login, SAML, Groovy, EasyMock, REST, Github, Maven
- Documentation: Blog posts, Product Guide, Tutorials, Examples, reStructuredText, markdown
- Customer Support

#### Sr. Software Developer at Freelance

June 2013 - June 2014 (1 year 1 month)

- Member of the (Kanban managed) core development team building a multi-tenant cloud-based authentication and user-management service.
- Achievements: Integration of Hazelcast (clustering and highly scalable data distribution platform) into the core backend service. LDAP/AD to MySQL synchronization
- Technologies: Java, Spring, REST+JSON, EasyMock, PowerMock, Vaadin, Javascript, Git, Maven, Hibernate, MySQL, Apache Shiro

## Red Hat Consultant - Open Source Developer at Red Hat

April 2011 - June 2013 (2 years 3 months)

- Release Engineer Consultant: Owner of the definition, implementation and guidance for company-wide Continuous Delivery strategy involving coordination with Architectural, Development, Configuration, QA and IT teams.
- Achievements: Definition and implementation of Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment pipelines applied business-wide to 20 JBoss applications.
- Technologies: Jenkins, SVN, git, Java, JBoss, JON, Nexus, Maven, ant, Sonar, SVN, Python, Linux.
- Sr. Open Source Developer: Full-time contribution to embryonic JBoss open source ESB project called Switchyard (JBossESB evolution)
- Achievements: Switchyard and Apache Camel integration Definition and implementation of Forge commands Definition and implementation of regression testing strategy for Forge integration Development of Quickstart application to demonstrate use of automatic JAXB transformation based on JAXB annotations.
- Technologies: Eclipse, Java, Tattletale, git, XML, Forge, Maven, Arquillian, Camel, Web Services.

#### Business Consultant and Developer at Self Employed Java Web Developer

February 2007 - April 2012 (5 years 3 months)

- Entrepreneurial experience:
- Home-banking system for brokerage firm Web 360 Feedback System for HR Consulting firm Different ETL tools for Telemarketing firm CRM system for scrivener office Web accounting system for brokerage firm Online remote backup service owner.
- Sole responsible for all phases of each project: from requirements to maintenance.
- Technologies: Eclipse, SVN, Maven, Java, Hibernate, MySQL, Tomcat, RMI, jZeno, scripting, AutoIT

#### **Engineering Support Team Leader at Intel Corporation**

November 2009 - April 2011 (1 year 6 months)

- Team Leader of Engineering Support Area (11/2009-04/2011): Planning, creation, execution and tracking of a four-member team with reports to management areas. Backend infrastructure monitoring, issue tracking and issue solving within SLAs.
- Achievements: Creation of a new Engineering Support area for a high availability multi-client backend platform Definition, emplacement and execution of objectives, tools, processes and SLAs Implementation of a monitoring framework to proactively detect issues Creation and execution of continuous improvement process Creation, reporting and management of operational and business dashboards.
  - Technologies: Splunk, SQL Server, SOAP, .Net, Jira, SVN.

#### **Software Engineer at Intel Corporation**

July 2006 - November 2009 (3 years 5 months)

- Different roles in Multiple Engineering Projects (06/2006-11/2009):
- Technical Leader: Definition and development of the backend logging strategy for a distributed service-enabling platform (.Net, .Net Enterprise Library, Splunk)
- Software Configuration Manager (SCM): Definition and documentation of SW Configuration Management Plan Owner of SW Releases Continuous Integration tool in place (Bamboo)
- Sr SW Developer: Definition, development and showcase of a cloud computing infrastructure prototype for automatic provisioning of SOA applications (SCA, Java, Web Services, CIM, Xen and Nagios)
- Open Source Representative: Contribution and evangelization of Apache Tuscany within Intel.
- Quality Assurance: Creation and execution of automatic test cases Creation of automatic testing framework to execute remote test cases (Java, SSH, XML, Struts)
- Tech leader and mentor: In charge of two different internship projects: a- Migration from Ant to Maven, b- .Net MEF Research.

#### **Apache Committer at The Apache Software Foundation**

January 2008 - June 2009 (1 year 6 months)

Apache Tuscany committer (SCA implementation):

- Achievements: Apache Committer – Third South American Committer - Ideologist, promoter and developer of a Marketplace sample application in Tuscany's distribution - Evangelization of Tuscany in a technical talk in JavaOne 2008 in San Francisco for 1000+ people - Several talks in different universities.

## Research Internship at SAP

July 2005 - January 2006 (7 months)

- Achievements: Performance testing of in-memory DB (based on my results SAP decided to acquire the DB Company and offered me a full-time job in South Korea to become part of the DB development team)
- Definition, evaluation and demonstration of data replication and federation database technologies for a distributed ubiquitous computing infrastructure Integration of a Smart Tag Windows library with a Java GUI.

- Technologies: C, pthreads, MaxDB, SAP Netweaver, KDevelop, gcc, Linux, Java, JNI.

#### Internship at Entrepids - Tandil, Argentina

December 2003 - May 2004 (6 months)

- Software Engineering Intern:
- Achievements: Implementation of business logic and user interface of an ecommerce website for the largest candy maker in the world (Arcor) currently being used by thousands of customers in Argentina.
- Responsibilities: Backend API definition Data model definition Backend developer Front-end developer
- Technologies: J2EE, Websphere, Hibernate, Struts, Portlets, DB2, SVN.

#### Education

#### Universidad Nacional del Centro de la Provincia de Buenos Aires

Master, Software Engineering, 1998 - 2005

#### **Technische Universität Darmstadt**

Schollarship, Databases and Distributed Systems, 2003 - 2003

#### Escuela de Educación Tecnica N2

Computational Technician, High School, 1992 - 1997

#### **Publications**

# Book: A High Level Pub/Sub Layer for Open Distributed Heterogeneous Environments: The Concept-Based Approach

VDM Verlag July 1, 2008

Authors: Mario Antollini

In this work the pub/sub paradigm is analyzed with the purpose to extend it to open distributed heterogeneous environments. On the basis of this analysis, a novel approach of combining ontologies and notifications is presented to support the correct interpretation of data coming from heterogeneous sources

#### Implementing a High Level Pub/Sub Layer for Enterprise Information Systems

Intl Conference on Enterprise Information Systems (ICEIS'06), Paphos, Cyprus, 2006 2006

Authors: Mario Antollini

In this paper we describe the concept-based approach as a high-level dissemination mechanism for distributed and heterogeneous event-based applications. We focus on the design and implementation issues of such a mechanism and show how it can be integrated on research prototypes or products and platforms

#### **Extending Rebeca to Support Concept-Based Addressing**

Proceedings of the Argentinean Symposium on Information Systems (ASIS'04) September 2004

Authors: Mario Antollini

### Dealing with Heterogeneous Data in Pub/Sub Systems: The Concept-Based Approach

International Workshop on Distributed Event-Based Systems (DEBS'04), Edinburgh, Scotland May 2004

Authors: Mario Antollini

## Languages

## **Spanish**

## **English**

# Skills & Expertise

Java

**SOA** 

**JMS** 

Maven

**Java Enterprise Edition** 

**Web Services** 

**Struts** 

**GWT** 

**XML** 

iOS development

**Objective-C** 

**Mobile Applications** 

Git

Ant

**Eclipse** 

Hibernate

**Software Development** 

Linux

**Subversion** 

**Tomcat** 

**MySQL** 

**Representational State Transfer (REST)** 

**Design Patterns** 

**Web Applications** 

**Oracle** 

JavaServer Pages (JSP)

**Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA)** 

#### **Interests**

Coding, Apple Products, Investing, Business, Theater, Traveling

# Mario Antollini

Java SDK Developer at Stormpath

antollinim@gmail.com



## 2 people have recommended Mario

"Mario is an independent professional who can take care of the end-to-end design, development and support of any distributed system. He has remarkable communication skills, which enables him to be the reference source for technical consulting. As a side note, Mario is one of only-several Apache committers in Latin American, status that can only be achieved with constant dedication and quality-oriented work within the Open Source community worldwide."

— **Andres More**, worked indirectly for Mario at Intel Corporation

"Mario is, without a doubt, a nice person and great professional. He is a good researcher, brings new and creative ideas to the table and suggest ways to improve our daily work. Overall a very polite and responsible engineer."

— Diego Naya, managed Mario at The Apache Software Foundation

Contact Mario on LinkedIn